James Loucks Fullstack developer

Vancouver, Canada 778-888-1496 james.loucks.codes@gmail.com

With a diverse history of 7+ years of experience, from serverless applications to dev-ops, and a background in 3D rendering. Proven technical leader; delivered project plans, managed timelines, and mentored new employees. Deep knowledge of security from the bare-metal to the application level, and of modern web frameworks.

Technical Summary

Bash, Bootstrap, C, C#, C++, Cg, Css, Express, Groovy, Hibernate, Html, Java, Javascript, Jvm, Lua, Mssql, Mysql, Node, Php, Python, React, Redux, Swing, Typescript, Wordpress

Professional History

Software Developer

Speedline Solutions May 2017 - present

Small development team focused on launching a new platform for online-ordering that integrates with legacy in-store offering. Hired as experienced web developer for work on maintaining modern best-practices.

- Evangelising modern node is conventions that can apply to project
- Design and implement features for the online ordering system
- Collaborate with team leads for interface and architectural design
- Technical resource for Node, React, and web 2.0

aws bootstrap continuous integration css express html kanban lambda microservices mobile node npm python react redux travis-ci typescript webpack windows

Software Developer

Boats Group Feb 2016 - May 2017

International company dealing with millions of users, providing global portals for posting boat sales. They have diverse technology stacks, but a flat heirarchy.

- Part of a global team that agile method to give weekly deliverables
- Designing and implementing highly-scalable next generation of internal APIs on NodeJs and Grails on top of MySQL and ElasticSearch and queues
- Lead several presentations to modernise and simplify the codebases
- Improved the onboarding process and guided new developers
- Technical lead for a top priority project
 - Responsible for design
 - Timeline estimation
 - Architectural decisions, after collaborating with several domain experts to learn the existing systems and dependencies
 - Communicated with the external client at the C-level
 - Carried it to completion on schedule

agile api-gateway aws bootstrap css elastic express groovy hibernate html java javascript jvm linux microservices mobile node npm responsive rest

System Analyst / Fullstack Developer

French School Board

November 2010 - February 2016

A small, diverse team focused on delivering all of the technical services and applications built specifically for francophone teachers in BC. We built fit-for-purpose applications to administer tests and track scores, custom integrations with larger software suites, and maintained learning software with updates and custom plugins.

- Design, implement, deploy, and maintain web applications
- Administer systems and provide security patching
- Manage cron jobs, and clone test-systems
- Lead training seminars for software we've rolled out into our organisation
- Wear many hats, filling any needs of the team; graphic design, audio recording, etc.
- Outside of assigned tasks
 - Encouraged adoption of newer programming conventions
 - Designing RESTful APIs
 - Use of modern web standards

All work was in French.

LAMP administration apache clang css gnu html java javascript jvm linux macOS mssql mysql php python redhat swing tomcat

Web Consultant & Visual Artist

Red on Black Music (Volunteer)

Oct 2014 - Oct 2015

Reacting quickly to short deadlines and changing requirements; develop changes to the website (plug-in administration, graphics, etc.) using a Kanban-style todo list.

css illustration kanban photoshop php wordpress

Education

System Administrator II Certificate

Red Hat Certification May 2012

From RedHat: "An IT professional who has earned the Red Hat Certified System Administrator (RHCSA®) is able to perform the core system administration skills required in Red Hat Enterprise Linux environments."

- Complete knowledge of the Linux command-line environments
- Deploy, configure, and maintain systems
- Manage securiy, including firewall and SELinux

bash crontab linux redhat selinux

Visual and Game Programming Diploma

Art Institute of Vancouver September 2010

Completion of the final project necessitated the command of modern programming paradigms, in-depth knowledge of asset pipelines and game engines (both Unreal and Unity).

- Team-based projects, SCM, Scrum, and Agile teams
- Implented design patterns and algorithms, such as search, and A*
- Acquired deep understanding of C++, C#, cg, and Python
- Memory management techniques, pointer arithmetic
- Networking in real-time with UDP and TCP/IP
- Focus on 3d math; implemented and used quaternion, matrix, and vector operations
- Designed and implemented shaders for custom engine, and exporters for Maya

c c# c++ cg javascript lua maya python scrum visual studio windows

IB Certificate

Port Moody Secondary School

June 2007

Excellence in Computer Science award, and attended the SFU problem solving competition, implementing solutions in Java.

c++ java